# **Alix Faudot**

# Front-End Web Developer

416-629-7578
alixfaudot@gmail.com
www.alixfaudot.com
linkedin.com/in/alixfaudot
github.com/alixfcodes

#### **About Me**

I'm a bilingual front-end developer with a passion for building responsive, accessible and engaging websites. With a background in customer service in the HR outsourcing industry, my past experiences have cultivated my strong communication and problem solving skills. I enjoy opportunities where I use my project management skills, attention to detail, and ability to work independently, while simultaneously contributing to a driven team with a shared vision.

#### **Skills**

HTML5 | CSS3 & SCSS | JavaScript | React | Responsive Design | RESTful APIs | Firebase | Git & Command Line Tools | Web Accessibility | Versions Controls | Wireframing | Scope Documentation | Paired Programming | Team-Based Development | Complex Problem Solving | Adaptability | Customer Service | Time Management | Continuous Improvement

# **Featured Projects**

# **Group Project (to come)**

React | API | SASS | Firebase

LIVE | REPO

Agency-like React application coordinating and communicating with a group of developers, delivering a fully functional product on a timeline, and collaborating on GitHub.

#### Project (to come)

React | API | SASS

LIVE | REPO

Project using React library to create an interactive application, working with external or third-party data source (API/ Firebase), error handling and UI design.

## **Feel Good Makeup**

JavaScript | API | HTML | SASS

LIVE | REPO

Paired programming project that stores user input and fetches data from the Makeup API to provide eco-conscious products.

# **Musings of Willow PSD Conversion**

HTML | SASS | Responsive Design

LIVE | REPO

Project focused to convert a static design into a multi-page, functional, responsive website.

# **Education**

# Juno College of Technology

Immersive Web Development Bootcamp | June - September 2022 Intro to JavaScript and Web Development | July - December 2020

Jean Moulin University | Lyon, France
Bachelor Degree in Management Science

# **Work Experience**

# Team Specialist/Trainer

**Alight Solutions** 

April 2019 - May 2022

- Monitored and analyzed customer escalations and interactions by reviewing recorded calls, online chats and customer surveys (CSAT); determining root causes, reporting analysis results, and providing feedback/coaching to agents
- Facilitated training for new hires and ongoing staff; trained over 100 employees
- Collaborated with team managers consistently achieving daily, monthly, and quarterly KPI targets above 80%
- Defused irate callers through supervisor line by utilizing conflict resolution techniques and soft skills

#### **Senior Pension Specialist**

Alight Solutions (formerly Aon Hewitt)

February 2016 - March 2019

- Acted as a main point of contact for retirees and employees set to retire; provided counselling on various pension policies and guidance throughout the entire retirement process
- Managed open investigations to ensure retirees' issues were resolved in a timely manner; additionally meeting monthly and quarterly client deliverables
- Collaborated with other domain teams on projects which improved the organization's benefits administration software in regards to maintenance of employee/retiree accounts and improving usability of customer portals

#### **Customer Service Representative**

Alight Solutions (formerly Aon Hewitt - contract)

October 2014 - January 2016

- · Handled customer inquiries/complaints/benefits/pension questions with accuracy while providing a seamless experience
- · Maintained CSAT rating over 95%, and consistently ranked in the top percentile in productivity and quality